<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sukrit Singh, PhD – Gaming</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Sukrit Singh, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live thoughts - Divinity Original Sin 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gaming/divinity-original-sin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gaming/divinity-original-sin-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Image with Captions and Markdown&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;style&gt;
        .image-container {
            text-align: center;
            margin-bottom: 1px;
        }
        .caption {
            font-size: 14px;
            color: #000; /* Black text */
            background-color: #fff; /* White background */
            border: 0px solid #000; /* Black border */
            padding: 5px;
            display: inline-block;
            margin-top: 1px;
        }
    &lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;there are no words.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;there-are-no-words&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#there-are-no-words&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I loved the first game, and this game has already gotten me hooked within 2 hours. The narration, dialogue, writing, and the combat. My god(s) the combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there&amp;rsquo;s plenty more to go, and so much to say, for now I&amp;rsquo;m just going to keep updating this post with my thoughts/experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anybody curious: I am playing it cooperatively with my friend online, using Red Prince and Fane as our characters (and Lohse and Beast as companions, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAREFUL. POTENTIAL SPOILERS BELOW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holy cow 8 well written origin stories!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen mention of the Bansuri (a flute from the Indian subcontinent) ever outside of south asian circles. Like. Ever. Props to Larian for highlighting some really diverse instruments in the soundtrack selection menu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magisters, y&amp;rsquo;all need to chill. There&amp;rsquo;s too much allegory here with modern political times and extremist stereotyping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;image-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gaming/figures-visuals/dos2-fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH&lt;/strong&gt; 
        (Also I&#39;m not sorry) 
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I AM THE WINNER OF THE FORT JOY ARENA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait why don&amp;rsquo;t our Source collars all get to come off at once?? I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether to be frustrated or impressed at sheer number of permutations to achieve objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Okay, from the second fight onwards we&amp;rsquo;ve had to establish a rule to not rush into everything separately. There&amp;rsquo;s so much to experience. Also these fights are TOUGH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DUAL WANDS BABY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;image-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gaming/figures-visuals/dos2-fig2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me using fire spells that set Beast on fire because he&#39;s 0.1 m too close to the enemy
&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awwww this dog on the beach is looking for his  master. :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh no we found his master and she&amp;rsquo;s been converted into an abomination. This is some FMA levels of heartstring tugging :(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LOHSE NO DO NOT KILL THE NICE NPC. I DON&amp;rsquo;T CARE THAT YOU’VE GOT A DEMON POSSESSING YOU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RED PRINCE MADE OUT WITH A LITERAL GODDESS. SCORE. LIZARDS GOT GAME.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;image-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gaming/figures-visuals/dos2-fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original image&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This meme, but also for spell Attribute requirements
&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of preparation/foresight you can have in exploring the map is incredible. What&amp;rsquo;s even cooler is how much the game rewards you taking the time to explore your options, and thinking about best tactical approach to an encounter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of encounters, this talking well which trades epic items for 150 gold is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; exploitable - not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s on purpose or not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOLY SHIT GIANT WORM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Mass Effect Andromeda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gaming/me-andromeda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gaming/me-andromeda/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Confession time: I never finished ME: Andromeda. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough to keep me going within the game. The plot didn&amp;rsquo;t make me feel connected to many characters, it felt too much like the standard Bioware fare. Nothing felt unique or relatable to Ryder. The environments weren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; to explore, and I felt like I was just playing Dragon Age Inquisition: Space edition. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much that I actively stopped playing the game, as I just found better games to play&amp;hellip;and with the whole &amp;ldquo;new trilogy&amp;rdquo; put on ice, there&amp;rsquo;s just no incentive to keep playing to find out what happens next&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything about this one yet, because I&amp;rsquo;m still playing it, but as I go along I&amp;rsquo;ll jot down thoughts I have as I go along. I&amp;rsquo;ll put spoiler warnings wherever I mention one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little disappointed by the character creator - Why can&amp;rsquo;t my Ryder have long hair if he&amp;rsquo;s male? Why does the female Ryder HAVE to have a ponytail? I feel like they didn&amp;rsquo;t include many options for hair/beards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait your dad sounds like Lex Luthor from DC&amp;rsquo;s Justice League animated Series! OH WAIT IT IS HIM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure how I feel yet about increased fluidity in the combat system. It&amp;rsquo;s a ton of fun to zip around the field, but not being able to snap to cover feels like it adds an unnecessary challenge to the gameplay. It&amp;rsquo;s not easier for me to be hit now - the dodge button makes me flit incredibly fast and makes it easier in fact to not be hit, but its disorienting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the new class/point assignment system. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel locked into a single class anymore, but I am still clearly building towards something very powerful and highly specialized (p.s. VANGUARDS FTW- they&amp;rsquo;re still incredibly powerful)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler warning  The entire &amp;ldquo;ancient tech&amp;rdquo; stuff just feels very Halo-esque. Like at any point I&amp;rsquo;m expecting either a bunch of monks to start singing, or to turn into the Master Chief&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review - Divinity Original Sin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gaming/divinity-original-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gaming/divinity-original-sin/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Image with Captions and Markdown&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;style&gt;
        .image-container {
            text-align: center;
            margin-bottom: 1px;
        }
        .caption {
            font-size: 14px;
            color: #000; /* Black text */
            background-color: #fff; /* White background */
            border: 0px solid #000; /* Black border */
            padding: 5px;
            display: inline-block;
            margin-top: 1px;
        }
    &lt;/style&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Divinity: Original Sin&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;divinity-original-sin&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#divinity-original-sin&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;by far one of the most challenging, varied, and fun games I have played in a long time. It combines the best of many RPGs - challenging, complicated turn-based combat and the excitement and stunning visuals of action-adventure games.
I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil any plot - but suffice it to say that the plot escalates in scale very quickly. D:OS is set in the land of Rivellon (like previous Divinity games) where magic, monsters, and everything in between reside. However, along with magic, there is a corrupt semi-divine-energy called Source that many wicked folks use: These wicked folk are called Sourcerers (har har). You play as a Source Hunter - a guild of folk dedicated to dealing with Sourcery (har har). Starting in the small coastal city of Cyseal, you investigate the murder of a city council member. However, not everything is as it seems and very quickly you become embroiled in cults, conspiracies, and plot threads of cosmic, world-ending proportions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;image-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gaming/figures-visuals/dos1-fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You thought Marvel&#39;s Infinity War was the most ambitious crossover in history?&lt;/strong&gt; What about Geralt the Witcher as a Source Hunter. 
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;D:OS lets you experience the chaos with a friend.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;dos-lets-you-experience-the-chaos-with-a-friend&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#dos-lets-you-experience-the-chaos-with-a-friend&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the world-ending threat level might be a familiar trope for many experienced RPGers, one thing D:OS does to set itself apart is that it gives you two protagonists to create and customize. You are able to control both of them in terms of skills, dialogue and combat - along with two other NPC companions. This gives you a whole new layer of options, mechanics, and playstyles to mix and match as you explore and fight your way around Rivellon. Furthermore, there are an immense number of options, items, skills, and powers to learn. A lack of preset builds means you can mix and match any combination of skills, stats, and abilities as you wish. However, it would behoove you to complement the two protagonists skills and abilities (ie. One tank and one mage, or one tank and one archer). This will give you more options in combat, preventing yourself being caught in a corner that you can&amp;rsquo;t get out of (and believe me, there are plenty of opportunities already to make your encounters harder without handicapping yourself with limited options).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with giving you two protagonists, the developers included a co-op mode. You and your co-op buddy each take one of the two protagonists and build them however you each wish. Of course, while you will have to work together in combat and dungeon crawls (whether you like it or not, really), you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to disagree on how you want to roleplay or make choices. You can settle your differences over a healthy game of Rock, Paper, Scissors (best of 5, but winner decides how things go down if there&amp;rsquo;s disagreement). Along with some semi-friendly RPS, you and your friend will have &amp;ldquo;dual dialogues&amp;rdquo; between the protagonists where you can express thoughts/concerns over recent events and happenings. Be careful what you say though - your responses/comments will provide you &amp;ldquo;trait points&amp;rdquo; which can provide useful bonuses suiting your character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Combat is where D:OS really stands out.&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terrain, like high ground or wet puddles, actually makes a difference, and being able to leverage your surroundings adds new depth to the combat that I had never experienced before. Moving barrels and carts around the fighting area and destroying them as needed to create cover is just one of many things you can do with your environment. You can even blanket the ground under your enemies with elemental traps and obstacles. Facing a lot of enemy archers? Just throw an oil barrel (yes, throw, but you need a strong character) and drop in a fireball - the resulting smoke cloud will blind enemy archers and prevent them from firing at you. Fights are challenging, and D:OS does not do any sort of hand holding when it comes to figuring out which combination of elements work. It gives players the opportunities and openings throughout the game to discover mechanics by yourself. I cannot recommend enough to explore the elemental combinations any time you can - D:OS is a game where knowledge is power, and tactical know-how can change an incredibly difficult encounter to something that ends satisfyingly quickly, because you came prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;image-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/gaming/figures-visuals/dos1-fig3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original image&#34; width=&#34;900&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My coop buddy and I utlilized the &#34;You distract and I&#39;ll become a stealth bush&#34; more than we probably should have.
&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;D:OS is an onion.&lt;span class=&#34;hx-absolute -hx-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;dos-is-an-onion&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#dos-is-an-onion&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of layers you won&amp;rsquo;t find unless you explore, there are a lot of different ways to handle it, and there will be some tears (both from combat frustration and lamenting over the consequences of some of your choices). It is a brutal, unforgiving game that leads you through an ultimately delicious and rewarding journey, and there is a distinct sense of victory and satisfaction when you complete the game. You can probably play through it casually without much thinking, but then you would miss out on the various hidden gems this game has to offer. It takes a tongue-in-cheek story with fantasy tropes and cosmic scale and weaves it into an original, surprisingly refreshing plot where stakes feel real. The combat is fresh, dynamic, and forces the players to strategize. Chaos and fun alike are doubled when you play with a friend. It stands unrelenting and proud in it&amp;rsquo;s complexity and rich detail, particularly in an age of gaming where many games settle for walking their players through all their mechanics. Divinity: Original Sin is truly one of a kind, and sets a high bar for any RPG I&amp;rsquo;ll be playing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
